[{"ans":"both a and c","language":"English","op1":"click on the new button.","op2":"both a and c","op3":"use the file new command","op4":"none of the above","question":"create a new blank presentation you could."},{"ans":"edit","language":"English","op1":"insert","op2":"slideshow","op3":"format","op4":"edit","question":"in which menu change case command appears"},{"ans":"in the custom animation task pane open effects of sun and shade the sound to play for the desired number of slides","language":"English","op1":"in the custom animation task pane open effects of sun and shade the sound to play for the desired number of slides","op2":"using the record sound feature press the record button and play your music as you click through the hall sensor","op3":"using the play CD audio track features set the CD to play for the desired number of task","op4":"all of the above","question":"how do you make an insert sound file play continuously over several slides"},{"ans":"title box","language":"English","op1":"textbox","op2":"placeholder","op3":"bulletpoint","op4":"title box","question":"all area on flight that holds that takes to will appear in the presentation out line is a ______"},{"ans":"all of the above","language":"English","op1":"create a professional and consistent look for your data","op2":"choose between standard table format that include border shading font colours and other formatting options","op3":"easily apply a consistent format through a workbook","op4":"all of the above","question":"the purpose of auto format command in excel is"},{"ans":"all of the above","language":"English","op1":"a search engine does not discriminate between good and bad sites","op2":"I search engine display all web pages that contains your keyword and main list 1000 of an order result","op3":"a dictionary is a second attempt to categorise the best site available for a given subject for topic","op4":"all of the above","question":"which of the following statements about search engine and documentaries is true"},{"ans":"all of the above","language":"English","op1":"130000","op2":"500000","op3":"1.1e+2","op4":"all of the above","question":"which one of the following can be entered as a number in a cell"},{"ans":"spider","language":"English","op1":"spider","op2":"packets","op3":"cookies","op4":"none of the above","question":"which of the following search engine continuously sense of that start on a homepage of server and purpose all links stepwise"},{"ans":"instant messaging","language":"English","op1":"instant messaging","op2":"email","op3":"usenet","op4":"blog","question":"what would you use for immediate real time communication with friend"},{"ans":"packet switching","language":"English","op1":"circuit switching","op2":"packet switching","op3":"hybrid switching","op4":"none of the above","question":"the internet uses"},{"ans":"bite bit field record file database","language":"English","op1":"bite bite record field file database","op2":"bite bit field record file database","op3":"bikebot record file field database","op4":"bit byte field record file database","question":"the ascending order of a data hierarchy"},{"ans":"application","language":"English","op1":"system software","op2":"microcomputer","op3":"documentation","op4":"application","question":"software instruction intended to safety user a specific processing need are called"},{"ans":"data in more useful or intelligible form","language":"English","op1":"RAW","op2":"data","op3":"data in more useful or intelligible form","op4":"alphanumeric data problem","question":"in computer terminology information means"},{"ans":"arithmetic logic unit","language":"English","op1":"keyboard","op2":"printer","op3":"tape","op4":"arithmetic logic unit","question":"which of the following is a part of the central processing unit"},{"ans":"knowing what a computer can and cannot do","language":"English","op1":"ability to write computer programs","op2":"knowing what a computer can and cannot do","op3":"knowing computer related vocabulary","op4":"ability to assemble computers","question":"what is mean by computer literacy"},{"ans":"graphical presentation","language":"English","op1":"word processing","op2":"spreadsheet","op3":"database","op4":"graphical presentation","question":"the software application that is used to most often is"},{"ans":"both circular task and sector","language":"English","op1":"circular task only","op2":"sectors only","op3":"both circular task and sector","op4":"none of the above","question":"floppy disk contains"},{"ans":"homepage","language":"English","op1":"homepage","op2":"master page","op3":"first page","op4":"banner page","question":"the first page that you normally view at a view site is"},{"ans":"to display a drop down list of justification options","language":"English","op1":"to display a drop down list of justification options","op2":"to display the four options for aligning text","op3":"to open the justification dialogue box","op4":"to centre the current line","question":"what is the function of justification button on the toolbar"},{"ans":"2","language":"English","op1":"2","op2":"4","op3":"8","op4":"16","question":"the binary number system has a best"},{"ans":"does calculations using addition subtraction multiplication and division","language":"English","op1":"check data for accuracy","op2":"does logical comparison such as equal to greater than less than both","op3":"does calculations using addition subtraction multiplication and division","op4":"c and b both","question":"the arithmetic logic unit performs following actions"},{"ans":"first information is transferred to main memory and form their the CPU read","language":"English","op1":"directly","op2":"first information is transferred to main memory and form their the CPU read","op3":"through registers","op4":"none of this","question":"CPU read the information from secondary memory"},{"ans":"an input device to produce good quality graphics","language":"English","op1":"an input device to produce good quality graphics","op2":"and output device to produce drawing and graphics","op3":"how fast output device using camera lenses","op4":"none of this","question":"a plotter is"},{"ans":"menu bar","language":"English","op1":"buttons","op2":"menu bar","op3":"toolbar","op4":"None","question":"_______is a collection of buttons which represents various operations that can be carried out within an application"},{"ans":"mathematical incentive scientific applications","language":"English","op1":"input output incentive processing","op2":"mathematical incentive scientific applications","op3":"data retrieval operations","op4":"none of these","question":"supercomputer are primarily used for"},{"ans":"menu bar","language":"English","op1":"menu bar","op2":"tool bar","op3":"status bar","op4":"it display the name of the document or applications","question":"the top most bar in any application window is the ______"},{"ans":"always use bleach to send message in different networks","language":"English","op1":"cannot address many users","op2":"does not provide protection given to first class mail","op3":"always use bleach to send message in different networks","op4":"none of this","question":"email"},{"ans":"CorelDRAW","language":"English","op1":"CorelDRAW","op2":"MS Excel","op3":"MS word","op4":"none of this","question":"which of the following is graphical package"},{"ans":"open the format menu","language":"English","op1":"open the format menu","op2":"to click the line spacing button","op3":"to select the paragraph you want to change","op4":"to open the paragraph menu","question":"what is the first step in MS word in changing line spacing"},{"ans":"multimedia devices","language":"English","op1":"pointing devices","op2":"pen input device","op3":"data collection devices","op4":"multimedia devices","question":"a mouse drag bill and joystick are example of"},{"ans":"file by some alternative names","language":"English","op1":"for saving the file for the first time to save","op2":"file by some alternative names","op3":"to save file in a format other than word","op4":"all of the above","question":"the save as dialogue box can be used"},{"ans":"you copy other text","language":"English","op1":"you got other text","op2":"you shut down your computer","op3":"you copy other text","op4":"all of the above","question":"the contents of the clipboard remains the same until"},{"ans":"all of the above","language":"English","op1":"you wish to add emphasize to particular paragraph","op2":"you wish to add and draw lines above and below or left or right of paragraph","op3":"you wish to surround the paragraph with different style of box","op4":"all of the above","question":"you probably use borders in world where"},{"ans":"to both character as well as paragraph selection","language":"English","op1":"two paragraphs election only","op2":"two character selection only","op3":"to both character as well as paragraph selection","op4":"none of the above","question":"the formatting toolbar option are applied"},{"ans":"create a new page at bottom of the document","language":"English","op1":"create a new page at the instruction.","op2":"create a new page at bottom of the document","op3":"create a new page that cannot be detected","op4":"create a blank page at the top of the document","question":"page break is used to do what"},{"ans":"format","language":"English","op1":"format","op2":"tools","op3":"insert","op4":"table","question":"in which word menu letter Wizard command appears"},{"ans":"table","language":"English","op1":"table","op2":"format","op3":"insert","op4":"tool","question":"in word split cells command appears in _______ menu"},{"ans":"worksheet","language":"English","op1":"square","op2":"cubicle","op3":"sale","op4":"worksheet","question":"in excel the intersection of a row and column is called"},{"ans":"in its default setting a word processor does not highlight the text","language":"English","op1":"in its default setting a word processor does not highlight the text","op2":"hibernating heaven you are dealing with the paint call amina text","op3":"by hibernating the look after justified days column will look greatly improved","op4":"Microsoft word highpoints text in its default setting","question":"one of the statements is not true"},{"ans":"chart sheet","language":"English","op1":"chart sheet","op2":"embedded sheet","op3":"workbook","op4":"view chart","question":"a chart on same spreadsheet it's called"},{"ans":"Netscape","language":"English","op1":"Netscape","op2":"Adobe edge","op3":"Firefox","op4":"Chrome","question":"first graphical browser for the www"},{"ans":"a r p a n e t","language":"English","op1":"a r p a n e t","op2":"nsf net","op3":"v net","op4":"inet","question":"the network is planted seed of internet"},{"ans":"all of the above","language":"English","op1":"presented by speaker","op2":"browser by individual","op3":"browser at kiosk","op4":"all of the above","question":"online is a PowerPoint slideshow options"},{"ans":"a and b both","language":"English","op1":"fill weekdays","op2":"fill series","op3":"a and b both","op4":"none of this","question":"in Excel shortcut film menu contains"},{"ans":"both a and b","language":"English","op1":"set print area from file menu","op2":"set print area from file page setup","op3":"both a and b","op4":"none of this","question":"to print specific area in Excel"},{"ans":"सही","language":"Hindi","op1":"सही","op2":"गलत","op3":"बता नही सकते","op4":"इन्मे से कोई भी नही","question":"माऊस 1 इनपुट उपकरण है"},{"ans":"abs","language":"English","op1":"char","op2":"len","op3":"var","op4":"abs","question":"which of the following is not text function"},{"ans":"abs","language":"English","op1":"char","op2":"len","op3":"var","op4":"abs","question":"which of the following is not text function"},{"ans":"abacus","language":"English","op1":"abacus","op2":"calculator","op3":"anatur","op4":"none of above","question":"first computer is"},{"ans":"advanced micro devices","language":"English","op1":"advantage micro distance","op2":"and mad dam","op3":"advanced micro devices","op4":"none of the above","question":"AMD stands for"},{"ans":"compact disk recordable","language":"English","op1":"compact disk recordable","op2":"collect data radium","op3":"colour data ring","op4":"none of the above","question":"CD_R stands for"},{"ans":"optical mark reader","language":"English","op1":"optical mark reader","op2":"optical mark reading","op3":"optical mark radar","op4":"none of the above","question":"OMR stands for"},{"ans":"local area network","language":"English","op1":"local area network","op2":"limited area network","op3":"limit and notice","op4":"none of the above","question":"lAN stands for"},{"ans":"world wide web","language":"English","op1":"world wide web","op2":"world wide websites","op3":"world wider web","op4":"none of the above","question":"www stands for"},{"ans":"terra byte","language":"English","op1":"tina byte","op2":"terra byte","op3":"team byte","op4":"none of the above","question":"TB stands for"},{"ans":"basic input output system","language":"English","op1":"basic input output system","op2":"BIO settlement","op3":"BIOSSS","op4":"none of the above","question":"what is the full form of BIOS"},{"ans":"ctrl+c","language":"English","op1":"ctrl+B","op2":"ctrl+c","op3":"ctrl+A","op4":"none of the above","question":"what is the shortcut key of copy"},{"ans":"ctrl+X","language":"English","op1":"ctrl+X","op2":"ctrl+C","op3":"ctrl+M","op4":"none of the above","question":"what is the shortcut key for CUT"},{"ans":"ctrl+V","language":"English","op1":"ctrl+V","op2":"ctrl+A","op3":"ctrl+B","op4":"none of the above","question":"what is the shortcut key for PASTE"},{"ans":"ctrl+B","language":"English","op1":"ctrl+C","op2":"ctrl+B","op3":"ctrl+A","op4":"none of the above","question":"what is the shortcut key for BOLD"},{"ans":"F1","language":"English","op1":"F1","op2":"F2","op3":"F4","op4":"none of the above","question":"what is the shortcut key for help"},{"ans":"none of the above","language":"English","op1":"F2","op2":"F3","op3":"F4","op4":"none of the above","question":"what is the shortcut key for search"},{"ans":"ctrl+Alt+Del","language":"English","op1":"ctrl+Alt+Del","op2":"Alt+Del","op3":"Del","op4":"none of the above","question":"what is the shortcut key for REBOOT"},{"ans":"ctrl+K","language":"English","op1":"ctrl+K","op2":"G","op3":"K","op4":"none of the above","question":"what is the shortcut key for HYPERLINK"},{"ans":"android","language":"English","op1":"C","op2":"C++","op3":"Java","op4":"android","question":"this is not programming language"},{"ans":"2","language":"English","op1":"1","op2":"2","op3":"3","op4":"4","question":"how many scroll bars can be visible on the text area if your document is over 200% …../"},{"ans":"insert","language":"English","op1":"view","op2":"refrence","op3":"insert","op4":"page layout","question":"what ribbon will you find where you can add a chart? "},{"ans":"page Layout","language":"English","op1":"view","op2":"refrence","op3":"insert","op4":"page layout","question":"What ribbon do you use to change margins? "},{"ans":"Number of pages in the document, word count,","language":"English","op1":"Number of pages in the document, word count,","op2":"size of margins, word count, web layout","op3":"Number of spellings errors, page number, document name","op4":"name of document, insert button, spell check","question":"What Can be Shown on the status bar?……"},{"ans":"Both (1) and (2)","language":"English","op1":"Is placed just below the standard toolbar","op2":"Is used to apply common formats to the worksheet test selection, like making it bold, italics, underlined or changing the font style and size","op3":"Both (1) and (2) ","op4":"None of the above","question":"The formatting toolbar/"},{"ans":"B$2:B$9","language":"English","op1":"B2:B9","op2":"$B$2:%B$9","op3":"B$2:B$9","op4":"None of the above","question":"To change the cell reference B2: B9 to an absolute row and column reference, you word enter it is as ….. "},{"ans":"All below","language":"English","op1":"All below","op2":"Can be built using function wizard ","op3":"Is a shortcut formula ","op4":"Is a readymade formula ","question":"A function in Excel ….. "},{"ans":"SUM","language":"English","op1":"FV","op2":"SUM","op3":"NPV","op4":"PMT","question":"Which of the following is not a financial function?"},{"ans":"ABS()","language":"English","op1":"CHAR()","op2":"LEN()","op3":"VAR()","op4":"ABS()","question":"Which of the following is not a text function?"},{"ans":"edu domain","language":"English","op1":"mail domain","op2":"in domain","op3":"edu domain","op4":"com domain","question":"Computers on the internet owned and operated by education institution form part of the …"},{"ans":"First Web page ","language":"English","op1":"User Web page ","op2":"First Web page ","op3":"Begining  Web page ","op4":"Home Page","question":"All web addresses start ….."},{"ans":"Home Page","language":"English","op1":"User Web page ","op2":"First Web page ","op3":"Begining  Web page ","op4":"Home Page","question":"When you start a web browser the first web page that gets loaded in the browser is called …"},{"ans":"both (1) and (2)","language":"English","op1":"E-mail, Telnet, Usenet ","op2":"Sound and movie files ","op3":"both (1) and (2) ","op4":"All internet communication tools ","question":"The world wide web integrates which of the following?"},{"ans":"TRUE","language":"English","op1":"TRUE","op2":"FALSE","op3":"-","op4":"-","question":"Using home tab you can perform editing functions such as cut, copy, paste, find  and replace etc. …"},{"ans":"TRUE","language":"English","op1":"TRUE","op2":"FALSE","op3":"-","op4":"-","question":"Using insert menu you can insert various object such as page numbers, headers and footers, picture etc…"},{"ans":"FALSE","language":"English","op1":"TRUE","op2":"FALSE","op3":"-","op4":"-","question":"using review tab you can aces to various utilities of word such as spess check, macros and mail merge etc. …"},{"ans":"TRUE","language":"English","op1":"TRUE","op2":"FALSE","op3":"-","op4":"-","question":"In MS word every command is available is ribbon. ……. MS"},{"ans":"FALSE","language":"English","op1":"TRUE","op2":"FALSE","op3":"-","op4":"-","question":"Formula bar is available in MS Word 2010…."},{"ans":"FALSE","language":"English","op1":"TRUE","op2":"FALSE","op3":"-","op4":"-","question":"To create a new worksheet, select worksheet from the file menu……"},{"ans":"FALSE","language":"English","op1":"TRUE","op2":"FALSE","op3":"-","op4":"-","question":"Cells are named by their positions either by rows or coloumns…."},{"ans":"FALSE","language":"English","op1":"TRUE","op2":"FALSE","op3":"-","op4":"-","question":"if the bold and underline buttons are appearing lighter than before, it means that they are currently in use …"},{"ans":"FALSE","language":"English","op1":"TRUE","op2":"FALSE","op3":"-","op4":"-","question":"Standard width of a column is 18.43……"},{"ans":"FALSE","language":"English","op1":"TRUE","op2":"FALSE","op3":"-","op4":"-","question":"To open a file quickly from the open dialog box, double click the file’s icon. "},{"ans":"TRUE","language":"English","op1":"TRUE","op2":"FALSE","op3":"-","op4":"-","question":"To specify multiple recipients of carbon copy of same mail message, Cc: field is used…"},{"ans":"FALSE","language":"English","op1":"TRUE","op2":"FALSE","op3":"-","op4":"-","question":"In SMTP, the message can be of any length…… SMTP"},{"ans":"FALSE","language":"English","op1":"TRUE","op2":"FALSE","op3":"-","op4":"-","question":"A protocol used for fetching e-mail from a mailbox is PQPI…"},{"ans":"FALSE","language":"English","op1":"TRUE","op2":"FALSE","op3":"-","op4":"-","question":"All incoming email messages are to be stored in the outbox folder"},{"ans":"TRUE","language":"English","op1":"TRUE","op2":"FALSE","op3":"-","op4":"-","question":"he email component of internet explorer is called  “outlook Express”"},{"ans":"TRUE","language":"English","op1":"TRUE","op2":"FALSE","op3":"-","op4":"-","question":"The input device to be used to get a printed diagram into a computer is the …"},{"ans":"input device","language":"English","op1":"output device","op2":"input device","op3":"game pad","op4":"scanner","question":"What type of device is a computer mouse?"},{"ans":"Hardware","language":"English","op1":"Software","op2":"Peripheral","op3":"Hardware","op4":"Storage","question":"any component of the computer you can see and touch is called"},{"ans":"Tools","language":"English","op1":"All below","op2":"Edit","op3":"Window","op4":"Tools","question":" In which menu spelling command appears"},{"ans":"show a context-sensitive menu ","language":"English","op1":"open the Display Properties dialog box ","op2":"show a context-sensitive menu ","op3":"open the Control Panel ","op4":"minimize all open applications","question":"A right click on the Windows desktop itself will _____. "},{"ans":"Right-aligned","language":"English","op1":"Justified","op2":"Right-aligned","op3":"Center-aligned ","op4":"Left-aligned ","question":"When numbers are typed inside a cell, the default alignment is:"},{"ans":"absolute cell reference ","language":"English","op1":"relative cell reference ","op2":"absolute cell reference ","op3":"mixed cell reference ","op4":"All of the above","question":"Cell address A$4 in a formula means it is a"}]
